Marguerite Mei

SUMMARY

Master of Management, Accounting & Finance, extensive Business & Analytical experience in **Financial Service**, **Retail** and **Consulting**, focusing on **Finance**, **Corp Accounting**, **CRM** and **Marketing**

✓ Finance

Proficiently apply financial modeling on budget, forecasting, revenue & variance analysis

✓ Customer Transaction

CRM Behavior Analysis and grouping using score-based RFM model

✓ Campaign & Marketing

Performance evaluation before and after

✓ Data & Tech Skills

MS Access, Advanced Excel, Marco, VBA, Python, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Snowflake, Google Analytics, Jira, ServiceNow, Draw.io, Visual Studio, Databricks, Jupyter Notebooks

Dashboard & Reporting

Financial Income Statement
Sales & Gross Margin Dashboard
CRM Segmentation Dashboards

EXPERIENCE

Analyst Intern | EDPYPF Services Inc., Markham, ON

Jan 2022 - Present

- Collected business requirement; delivered BRD to address scope, layout, KPI, workflow and specification
- Enterprise reporting automation using Access & Excel for Monthly income statement report
- Analyzed industry trends and customer data using SQL, Python and validated the data integrity gaps.
- Goal-oriented sales forecasting & expense-based budgeting for next year and specific forecasts for adjustment
- Designed **CRM dashboard** using Power BI to support management decision making & ensure effective action taking based on simplified interface whereas rich meaning of **business metric design**
- Conducted various analysis cases regarding store expansion, market share and campaign performance

Tools Used: Excel, VBA, Power BI, SQL Server, Snowflake, SQL, Google Analytics, jira, ServiceNow, draw.io

EXPERIENCE - PT

Industry Research Intern | Ginis Electronics Technology LLC

(Summers) May 2019 - Aug 2021

- Accounts bookkeeping maintenance and data reconciliation for GL, AP, AR in SQL DB
- Worked with 3rd party company on periodic adjustment, posting, auditing and financial reporting
- Communicated with bank, internal & external stakeholders on financing, insurance, securities, credit cards etc.
- Automated invoicing process using Excel Marco, VBA to upload data to accounting database.
- Managed 10+ marketing channels across industries seeking for business opportunities in short turnover periods
- Analyzed and grasped client core demands quickly; Well-prepared with business flow, objectives, and deliveries

Analyst Intern | Axis Communications Inc.

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Collaborated with stakeholders from sales and service teams to collect business requirements
- Prepared **SQL queries** for routine and ad hoc analysis
- Planned event for distributors training campaign, creating contents, tracking, analyzing subscribers
- Presented and praised by C-level clients for research-based insights, establishing new business opportunities

PROJECTS

•	Bell strategies to accelerate prepaid subscriber additions	May 2022
•	Brand, portfolio and competition analysis for ESTEE LAUDER	Feb 2022
•	Staples save & subscribe program strategy and expansion analysis	Sep 2021
•	DC inventory management - inbound, outbound and on-hand requirement analysis	Mar 2021
•	Case Analysis of Credit Risk Evaluation of a Bridge Loan	Jan 2021
•	Marty's Department Store – Customer Grouping & Campaign Analyses	Sep 2020
•	Customer based Brand Equity Management Project	Mar 2019

EDUCATION

- Master of Management, Accounting and Finance | University of Windsor | Sep 2020 Jun 2022
- Bachelor of Commerce with Honors | York University, ON | Sep 2014 Oct 2019
- Diploma certificate, Professional Accounting | Seneca College, ON | Sep 2019 Aug 2020
- Certificate: Google Analytics 2022 | Digital Campaign Google | SQL for Data Analysis Udcity 2022